TANTRUM She had got up very early in the morning and had worked hard in the
garden and she was tired and sleepy, so as soon as Martha had brought her supper
and she had eaten it, she was glad to go to
bed. As she laid her head on the pillow she murmured to
herself: "I'll go out before breakfast and work with Dicken and then afterward— —I
believe— —I'll go to see him." She thought it was the middle of the
night when she was wake by such dreadful sounds that she jumped out of bed in an
instant. What was it— —what was it? The next minute she felt quite sure she knew.
Doors were opened and shut and there were hurrying feet in the corridors and
someone was crying and screaming at the same time, screaming and crying in a
horrible way. "It's Colin," she said. "He's having one of those tantrums the nurse
called hysterics. How awful it sounds." As she listened to the sobbing
screams she did not wonder that people were so frightened that they gave him
his own way in everything rather than hear them. She put her hands over her
ears and felt sick and shivering. "I don't know what to do. I
don't know what to do," she kept saying. "I can't bear
it." Once she wondered if he would stop if she dared go to him and then she
remembered how he had driven her out of the room and thought that perhaps the
sight of her might make him worse. Even when she pressed her hands
more tightly over her ears she could not keep the awful sounds out. She hated them
so and was so terrified by them that suddenly they began to make her angry
and she felt as if she should like to fly into a tantrum herself and frighten
him as he was frightening her. She was was not used to anyone's tempers but her
own. She took her hands from her ears and sprang up and stamped her foot. "He ought
to be stopped! Somebody ought to make him stop! Somebody ought to beat him!" she cried
out. Just then she heard feet almost running down the corridor and her door
opened and the nurse came in. She was not laughing now by any means. She even looked rather
pale. "He's worked himself into hysterics," she said in a great hurry. "He'll do
himself harm. No one can do anything with him. You come and try, like a good child.
He likes you." "He turned me out of the room this morning," said Mary, stamping her foot with
excitement. The stamp rather pleased the nurse. The truth was that she had been
afraid she might find Mary crying and hiding her head under the bed clothes
That's right," she said. "You're in the right humor. You go and scold him. Give
him something new to think of. Do go, child, as quick as ever you can." It was
not until afterward that Mary realized that the thing had been funny as well as
dreadful— —that it was funny that all the grown-up people were so frightened that
they came to a little girl just because they guessed she was almost as bad as
Colin himself. She flew along the corridor coridor and the nearer she got
to the screams the higher her temper mounted. She felt quite wicked by the
time she reached the door. She slapped it open with her hand and ran across the
room to the for posted bed. "You stop!" she almost shouted. "You stop! I hate you!
Everybody hates you! I wish everybody would run out of the house and let you
scream yourself to death! You will scream yourself to death in a minute, and I wish you
would!" A nice sympathetic child could neither have thought nor said such
things, but it just happened that the shock of hearing them was the best
possible thing for this hysterical boy whom no one had ever dared to restrain or
contradict. He had been lying on his face beating his pillow with his hands and he
actually almost jumped around, he turned so quick Qui ly at the sound of the
furious little voice. His face looked dreadful, white and red and swollen, and
he was gasping and choking; but savage little Mary did not care an
atom. "If you scream another scream," she said, "I'll scream too— —and I can scream
louder than you can and I'll frighten you, I'll frighten you!" He actually had stopped screaming
because she had startled him so. The scream which had been coming almost
choked him. The tears were streaming down his face and he shook all
over. "I can't stop!" he gasped and sobbed. "I can't— —I
can't!" "You can!" shouted Mary. "Half that ails you is hysterics and temper— —just
hysterics— —hysterics— —hysterics!" and she stamped each time she said it. "I felt the
lump— —I felt it," choked out Colin. "I knew I
should. I shall have a hunch on my back and then I shall die," and he began to
rthe again and turned on his face and sobbed and wailed but he didn't
scream. "You didn't feel a lump!"
contradicted Mary fiercely. "If you did it was only a hysterical lump. Hysterics
makes lumps. There's nothing the matter with your horrid back— —nothing but
hysterics! Turn over and let me look at it!"
She liked the word "hysterics" and felt somehow as if it had an effect on him. He
was probably like herself and had never heard it before. "Nurse," she commanded, "come here and
show me his back this minute!" The nurse, Mrs. Medlock and Martha
had been standing huddled together near the door staring at her, their mouths half
open. All three had gasped with fright more than once. The nurse came forward as
if she were half afraid. Colin was heaving with great breathless sobs.
"Perhaps he— —he won't let me," she hesitated in a low voice. Colin heard her, however,
and he gasped out between two sobs: "Sh— —show her! She— —she'll see
then!" It was a poor thin back to look at when it was Beed Every rib could be
counted and every joint of the spine, though Mistress Mary did not count them
as she bent over and examined them with a solemn savage little face. She looked so sour and
old-fashioned that the nurse turned her head aside to hide the twitching of her
mouth. There was just a minute's silence, for even Colin tried to hold his
breath while Mary looked up and down his spine, and down and up, as intently as if
she had been the great doctor from London. "There's not a single lump there!"
she said at last. "There's not a lump as big as a pin— —except backbone lumps, and
you can only feel them because you're thin. I've got backbone lumps myself, and
they used to stick out as much as yours
do, until I began to get fatter, and I am not fat enough yet to hide them. There's
not a lump as big as a pin! If you ever say there is again, I shall
laugh!" No one but Colin himself knew what a effect those crossly spoken childish
words had on him. If he had ever had anyone to talk to about his secret
terrors— —if he had ever dared to let himself ask questions— —if he had had
childish companions and had not lay on his back in the huge closed house,
breathing an atmosphere heavy with the fears of people who were most of them
ignorant and tired of him, he would have found out that most of his fright and
illness was created by himself. But he had lain and thought of himself and his aches and
weariness for hours and days and months and years. And now that an angry
unsympathetic little girl insisted obstinately that he was not as ill as he
thought he was he actually felt as if she might be speaking the
truth. "I didn't know," ventured the nurse, "that he thought he had a lump on his
spine. His back is weak because he won't try to sit up. I could have told him
there was no lump there." Colin gulped and turned his face a little to look at
her could could you?" he said pathetically. "Yes, sir." "There!" said Mary, and she gulped too.
Colin turned on his face again and but for his long drawn broken breaths, which
were the dying down of his storm of sobbing, he lay still for a minute, though
great tears streamed down his face and wet the pillow. Actually the tears meant
that a curious great relief had come to him. Presently he turned and looked at
the nurse again and strangely enough he was not like a rajer at all as he spoke
to her. "Do you think— —I could— —live to grow up?" he said. The nurse was neither clever
nor soft-hearted but she could repeat some of the London doctor's words. "You
probably will if you will do what you are told to do and not give way to your
temper, and stay out a great deal in the fresh air." Colin's tantrum had passed and
he was weak and worn out with crying and this perhaps made him feel gentle. He put
out his hand a little toward Mary, and I am glad to say that, her own tantrum
having passed, she was softened too and met him halfway with her hand, so that it
was was a sort of making up. "I'll— —I'll go out with you, Mary," he
said. "I shun hate fresh air if we can find—" He remembered just in time to stop
himself from saying "if we can find the secret garden" and he ended, "I shall like
to go out with you if Dickon will come
and push my chair. I do so want to see Dickon and the fox and the
crow." The nurse remade the tumbled bed and shook and straightened the pillows.
Then she made Colin a cup of beef tea and gave a cup to Mary, who really was
very glad to get it after her excitement. Mrs. Medlock and Martha gladly
slipped away, and after everything was neat and calm and in order the nurse
looked as if she would very gladly slip away also. She was a healthy young woman
who resented being robbed of her sleep and she yawned quite openly as she looked at Mary,
who had pushed her big foot stol close to the four-posted bed and was holding Colin's
hand. "You must go back and get your sleep out," she said. "He'll drop off after a
while— —if he's not too upset. Then I'll lie down myself in the next
room." "Would you like me to sing you that song I learned from May Aya Mary
whispered to Colin. His hand pulled hers gently and he turned his tired ey eyes on her
appealingly. "Oh, yes!" he answered. "It's such a soft song. I shall go to sleep in a
minute." "I will put him to sleep," Mary said to the yawning nurse. "You can go if you
like." "Well," said the nurse, with an attempt at reluctance. "If he doesn't go to sleep
in half an hour you must call me." "Very well," answered
Mary. The nurse was out of the room in a
minute and as soon soon as she was gone Colin pulled Mary's hand
again. "I almost told," he said; "but I stopped myself in time. I won't talk and
I'll go to sleep, but you said you had a
whole lot of nice things to tell me. Have you— —do you think you have found out
anything at all about the way into the secret garden?" Mary looked at his poor little
tired face and swollen eyes and her heart relented yes yes she answered, "I think I
have. And if you will go to sleep I will tell you tomorrow His hand quite
trembled. "Oh, Mary!" he said. "Oh, Mary! If I could get into it I think I should live
to grow up! Do you suppose that instead of singing the a song— —you could just
tell me softly as you did that first day what you imagine it looks like
inside? I am sure it will make me go to sleep."
"Yes," answered Mary. "Shut your eyes." He closed his eyes and lay quite
still and she held his hand and began to speak very slowly and in a very low
voice. "I think it has been left alone so long— —that it has grown all into a lovely
tangle. I think the roses have climbed and climbed and climbed until they hang
from the branches and walls and creep over the ground— —almost like a strange gray
mist. Some of them have died but many— —are alive and when the summer comes there
will be curtains and fountains of roses. I think the ground is full of
daffodils and snow drops and lies and iris working their way out of the dark.
Now the spring has begun— —perhaps— —perhaps—" The soft drone of her voice was
making him stiller and stiller and she saw it and went on.
"Perhaps they are coming up through the grass— —perhaps there are clusters of
purple crocuses and gold ones— —even now.
Perhaps the leaves are beginning to break out and uncurl— —and perhaps— —the
gray is changing and a green GW veil is creeping— —and creeping over—
—everything. And the birds are coming to look at it— —because it is— —so safe and
still. And perhaps perhap perhaps— —perhaps—" very softly and slowly indeed,
"the robin has found a mate— —and is building a nest." And Colin was
asleep. CHAPTER